在与贵格会成员相处的早期，
Early on my time with quakers
我了解到一个叫澄心委员会的东西。
I learned about this thing called a Clearness Committee.
基本上我听到的是这样,
And it was basically the way it was described to me,
就好像说，你有些事情需要处理,
it's like you've got something you need to figure out,
有个问题需要解决
you have a problem you need to solve
或者有需要回答的问题。
or question you need to answer.
你不一定需要建议。
You don't necessarily need advice.
你可能知道你需要做什么，
You probably know what you need to do,
但你需要清除所有
but you need to clear through all the things that
干扰你的能力的东西，
are interrupting your ability to access what,
以获得你内心深处知道你需要做的事情，
in your heart of hearts know you need to do
这样你就需要一个澄心委员会。
so you can then have a clearness committee.
我有一个个人的祈祷。
I have a personal prayer.
我是泥土，塑造我吧！
I am the clay, mold me.
我是容器，填满我吧！
I am the vessel, fill me.
我是工具，使用我吧！
I am the instrument, use me.
但在试图决定如何最好地被使用时,
But in trying to decide how best to be used,
我需要别人的祈祷、支持和倾听。
I need the prayer and support and listening of others.
澄心委员会是
A Clearness committee is
一个由教友聚在的小团体，
a small group of Friends that gather and
基本上就是问你一些棘手的问题，
basically ask you tough questions about
会问，引领你的是什么，你关心的是什么,
what your leading is, what your concern is,
你内心发生了什么，你感觉到了什么。
what's happening inside you, what do you feel.
我们会定期举行
Well, people we regularly have,
所谓的婚姻澄心委员会。
what's called a Clearness Committee for marriage.
我们有关于人们是否真的
We have Clearance Committees about
被召唤去做他们正在考虑去做
whether people are actually called to do a ministry
某项事工的澄心委员会。
that they're thinking about.
我们有关于成员资格审核的澄心委员会。
We have clearness for membership.
我们会讨论这样的问题“你准备好加入公谊会了吗？”
Are you ready to join the Religious Society of Friends?
我认为，用贵格会的术语来说，澄心委员会
A Clearness Committee, I think, in Quaker terms,
在很大程度上与谦逊有关。
very much involves humility.
你是在向一个实体，
You are submitting yourself,
即会议的一部分，你的会众，呈现你自己，
generally voluntarily, to an entity that is
而这一般来说，是自愿的。
a part of your Meeting, your congregation.
很多人会召集澄心委员会，
A lot of people will convene a Clearance Committee
以澄清自己是否要结婚的,
if they are getting married,
或者要选择上哪所大学,
or if they're choosing what college to go to,
或者选择职业生涯的方向,
or choosing which direction to go in their career,
或者类似的东西。
or that sort of thing.
这就是我们为之命名澄心委员会这个名字的原因。
So that's where we get the name Clearness Committee.
这是关于清晰的会议，对一个决定变得清晰。
It's about clearness, becoming clear about a decision.
当召集小组会议时,
When we call this group together,
我们要找的是特定类型的人。
we're looking for very specific kinds of people.
我们要找的是善于倾听的人，
We're looking for people who are good at listening
并且不倾向于提供建议的人。
and who don't have a tendency to give advice.
他们应该是你生命中以及在你的
These should be people that are important in your life
社区生活中非常重要的人。
and in the life of your community.
但不要太接近你，
But not so close to you that
以至于他们会受到
they're going to be influenced by
你所做决定的某种影响。
your decision one way or the other.
他们在那里不是为了提供答案。
They're not there to provide answers.
他们在那里试图帮助你看清楚
They are there to try and help you see clearly
现在的情况什么，正在发生什么,
what the situation is, what's happening,
以及你该怎么做。
and what you should do about it.
这是你灵性团体的礼物，
It's a gift of your spiritual community,
他们对你说，“你不必独自挣扎。
saying, "You don't have to struggle alone.
我们是可以和你一起工作
Here are your companions that can work with you
并和你一起踏上这段旅程的同伴”
and go on this part of your journey with you",
对我来说，这在当今这个时代是非凡的。
which is, to me, phenomenal in this day and age.
我们可以如此有福气，我们的社区说,
That we could be so blessed that our community says,
“你不必独自面对。
"You don't have to do this alone.
我们会帮助你。”
We will help."
澄心委员会的准备工作是
The prep work for a Clearness Committee is that
书记员会及时找一个地方
the clerk will find a place in time
召集委员会成员,
and put together the committee,
然后委员会的焦点人物
and then the person who is the focus person of
将提前写一两页关于其议题的说明。
the committee will write a page or two in advance.
因此，焦点人物首先要做的是，
And so you start off by
向大家描述实际的情况。
actually describing the situation.
比如，让自己安顿下来，写下情况，这样，
Like, really sitting down, writing it out so that
每个人都可以看到它，你可以说，
everybody has access to it and you can say,
”好吧，事情是这样的,
"Okay, this is what's going on,
这就是为什么我很困惑。
and this is why it's confusing to me.
这些是我认为
These are what I perceive
在这种情况下我的选择。
my options to be in this situation.
我错过了什么吗?”。
What am I missing?".
澄心委员会所涉及的步骤
The steps involved in the actual Clearness Committee
事把委员召集到一起，并询问
are to come together and for the person who is
发起澄心委员会的焦点人物
asking for the Clearness Committee
他们想明晰的到底是什么。
to state what it is that they want clarity on.
他们在会上会陈述他们的问题或决策点。
So they state their problem or decision point.
虽然之前已发出议题说明,
Even though it's been passed out beforehand,
但我还会用自己的话说,
I say in my own words,
“这就是我所理解的情况”。
"This is the situation as I understand it".
然后，委员会应该提出一些澄清的问题，
Then the committee should ask clarifying questions
这些问题实际上只关心事实。
that are really just about facts.
比如，“你是说你要搬到
Like, "Did you mean you're moving to
美国的格鲁吉亚还是亚洲的格鲁吉亚?”。
Georgia in the U.S or Georgia in Asia?".
诸如此类的问题。
That kind of thing.
然后经过这段时间的询问
And then after this time of questioning,
我们坐下来等待。
we sit and we wait.
我曾参加过一个澄心委员会，
And I've been in Clearness Committees where
在那里坐着等了20分钟,
sitting and waiting lasted for 20 minutes,
还有一次，我在一个澄心委员会，
and I've been in Clearness Committees where
坐着等了三个小时。
sitting and waiting lasted for 3 hours.
通常，人们只是倾听，
So usually people will just listen
并一起维护这个空间，
and hold this space together,
并请求圣灵给他们带来清明。
and ask the Spirit to bring to them clarity.
委员会开始一起倾听焦点人物，
The committee starts listening together
然后提出更深入的属灵问题：
and asking deeper spiritual questions.
“你是否觉得上帝在召唤你去做这件事？”，
Do you feel that God is calling you to do this?
“如果你走这条路，
How do you see your life evolving
你认为你的生活会如何演变？”，
if you follow this path?
“如果你拒绝这个机会，
How do you see your life evolving
你如何看待你的生活演变？”。
if you turn away from this opportunity?
澄心委员会
So the questions that a Clearness Committee
所问的所有问题都是开放式的。
asks are all going to be questions that are open ended.
这会导致更多的自我反省,
And that lead to greater self-reflection,
更深入的祈祷，一级更富有想象力的
and to a deeper prayer and to a more imaginative
对问题或疑问的参与。
engagement with the problem or question.
在这一点上，
At that point,
委员会的作用是退后一步，倾听，
the committee's role is to step back and listen and
并真正让焦点人物进入明晰的过程
let the focus person for the clearness process really
在心智和属灵层面
respond to those questions at a deep
深入地回答这些问题。
heart mind and spirit level.
在这段（镜映）时间里，很多时候人们会
So out of that time, a lot of times people will
分享他们注意到的事情。
share things that they noticed.
也许他们会分享,
Maybe they'll share,
“当你谈到这个想法的时候，
"I noticed your eyes really light up
我注意到你的眼睛亮了”，
when you talked about this idea",
或者，“当你谈论这个决定的时候，
or "I noticed a change in your body posture
我注意到你身体姿势有所变化”。
when you're talking about this decision".
在这方面，我的经验是，
But my experience in this is that
当你召集这群人
when you've got this group of people
一起聆听焦点人物的议题时,
gathered to listen around this issue,
每个人都会听到一点点
each person is going to hear
上帝的声音以及帮助焦点人物向前走的话语。
a little piece of God's voice, of away forward.
很多时候，焦点人物自己会
A lot of times, the person themselves will
开始感觉到自己内心的明晰，
start feeling that clarity in themselves and
而且将能够在一定程度上命名它，
will be able to name it to some degree
他们会这样说,
and to be able to say,
“是的，当你分享的时候,
"Yes, when you shared that,
我真的觉得是这样的”
I really felt like that rang true",
或者，“那感觉就在我的身体或属灵里”。
or "That felt right within my body or my spirit".
我曾带着对将要发生的事情的
I've come into a Clearness Committee
先入为主的概念进入澄心委员会，
with a preconceived notion of what's going to happen,
但每次都被吹得天花乱坠。
and it gets blown out of the water every single time.
这种方式有点滑稽。
It's kind of hilarious that way.
我曾参加过一个澄心委员会，在那里小组
I've been on Clearness Committees where the group
发现焦点人物对结婚感到不明晰,
found that people weren't clear to get married,
或者那个成员
for instance, or that membership
可能还需要一点时间来明晰,
might need to take a little more time,
或者可能需要召开第2、3或4次会议，
or that there might need to be 2 or 3 or 4 meetings
在明晰部分问题前
faced that over a number of months before
花几个月时间里面对这个问题。
we get at the clearness part of things.
我觉得这在很多方面是有帮助的。
I think that's helpful in a couple of ways.
它在“是的”方面很有帮助，比如,
It's helpful in the "yes", like of,
“啊，是的，这就像个引领，所以没有点自我怀疑，没问题的，
"Ah, yes, like this was a leading, so okay self-doubt
就像，有其他的委员会成员，
like, take that, there's a committee of other
他们已经倾听并听到了我的心声！”。
friends who have listened and heard!".
这也像,
It's also like,
我可以为 "不 "而欢欣鼓舞。
I can rejoice in the "no".
比如，当澄心委员会以“等待”,
Like, when a Clearness Committee ends in a "wait",
或“那不是我想的那样”结束。
or like, "That wasn't what I thought it was".
这就像来自上帝的声音，
Then that's coming from God
而我感觉在那个“不”
and I can feel so much more comfortable
或者那个“等等”终舒服多了，
in that "no" or in that "wait"
而不是，“我要说‘不’，或者‘等等’，
than just like, "Well I really said no, or wait,
但这只是我自己的自我怀疑。”。
but it was just like my own self-doubt".
通通不见了。
That's gone.
在澄心委员会最后，
That's kinda out of the picture
这有点出乎意料。
at the end of a Clearness Committee.
有时候，你还没得到明晰,
Sometimes you don't come to clarity,
所以当这种情况发生时，有点令人沮丧。
so that's kind of a bummer when that happens.
但这绝对不罕见,
But it definitely is not uncommon,
所以如果这种事发生在你身上，别担心,
so if that happens to you, don't worry,
你并不是贵格会的失败者。
you're not a failure at Quakerism.
你可以再试一次，
You can try again or
或者你可以让从那个社区中
you can allow the wisdom that did emerge
出现的智慧来告知你的决定。
out of that community to inform your decision.
在这个忠实的等待和聆听的空间里,
In this space of faithful waiting and listening,
坦率地用爱倾听
and frankly listening with love
焦点人物的问题,
for the person who has the question,
意味着当我们每个人以不同的方式
means that when we bring that love together
将自己持有的爱凝聚在一起时，
in the different ways each individual holds that,
即使没有明晰的结果,
even if no clarity comes from it,
有一种被我们的社区所拥有的爱的感觉，
there is a sense of being held in love by our community
这可以使即使缺乏明晰度
that can make the lack of clarity
也不再像以前那么可怕。
not as scary as it used to be.